# VINCENT ADAMS vince1211@yahoo.com (702) 557- 6707

#### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Thirteen plus years of Commercial Real Estate, Right of Way, and Site Acquisition management level experience

Five plus years of Permitting/Zoning management level experience in support to design engineers, planners, surveyors, property owners and construction staff to acquire necessary right of way, real property easements, Special Use Permits, jurisdictional approval, zoning compliance, and Land Use Licenses

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science/Urban Studies Graduated: May 1997 University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee

Bachelor of Arts/History Graduated: December 1991 University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee

#### **RELATED EXPERIENCE**

# Atkins Right of Way Agent II

**April 2019 – August 2020** 

- Supervise the preparation of department technician acquisition packages of real property
- Negotiate acquisitions of real property with property owners, attorneys, real estate professionals
- Obtain right-of-way occupancy permits on behalf of company clients

# Nevada Department of Transportation Right of Way Agent II

April 2016-April 2019

- Responsible for monitoring local public agencies use of Federal Highway Funds to ensure compliance with the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 (Uniform Act)
- Regularly serve as project managers with responsibility for project status reporting, coordination of activities with other disciplines and divisions, project timelines, and consultant contract administration.
- Arrange for maintenance and repairs; write rental agreements, commercial, multiuse, and airspace leases and licenses, solicit bids for contracts, prepare contract documents and inspect work prior to final payment.

# Tectonic Engineering & Surveying Site Acquisition Specialist II

## **February 2014 - March 2015**

- Managed and negotiated site acquisition contracts for company wireless communication increased bandwidth expansion projects within designated schedules and budget guidelines
- Responsible for lease negotiations and renewals of governmental permits (DOT, BLM,)
- Management level permitting/zoning experience in support to design engineers, planners, surveyors, property owners and construction staff to acquire necessary right of way, real property easements, Special Use Permits, jurisdictional approval, zoning compliance, and Land Use Licenses

### **Best Rate Referrals**

#### **January 2013 – January 2014**

### Account Executive, Las Vegas, NV

- Business Development work for Mortgage Lead Generation Company
- Contacted prospects from database and cold calls from Mortgage/Credit Industry
  - Negotiated business terms according to corporate guidelines

# Discount Retail Store Services

#### **January 2012 - January 2013**

## Director of Real Estate, Las Vegas, NV

- Director for a team of 8 research assistants/site locators
- Develop and maintain a network of relationships with retailers, developers, brokers and landlords to facilitate an effective long-term strategy for continued growth
- Drafted and negotiated LOI's, Lease renewals, and expansions of commercial retail leases
- Obtained estimates from vendors and wrote POs, tracked purchases and follow up on deliveries made to construction sites on Tenant Improvement projects

# Discount Retail Store Services Director of Real Estate, Las Vegas, NV

June 2003 - June 2007

- Director for a team of 8 research assistants/site locators
- Negotiated over 150 commercial retail real estate contracts totaling 15 million dollars
- Develop and maintain a network of relationships with retailers, developers, brokers and landlords to facilitate an effective long-term strategy for continued growth
- Obtained estimates from vendors and write POs, tracked purchases and follow up on deliveries made to construction sites on Tenant Improvement projects

#### Wireless Facilities, Inc. (WFI)

#### July 1999- May 2003

#### Site Acquisition Specialist, Milwaukee, WI

- Negotiated over 150 commercial real estate contracts totaling over 50 million dollars
- Responsible for lease negotiations and renewals of governmental permits (DOT, BLM,)
- Read and understand construction documents (plans, blueprints) to liaison construction design from Architects and Contractors to landlords and governmental agencies